A Guide to the Papers of Dennis L. McCurdy, 1977-1979
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
Papers of Dennis L. McCurdy undated, 1977-1979
Special Collections and University Archives, Patricia W. and J. Douglas Perry Library, Old Dominion University
42
1 Hollinger document case
McCurdy, Dennis L.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Open to researchers without restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift from Dennis L. McCurdy, November 12, 1979.
Historical Information
Dennis McCurdy attended the University of North Carolina, Greensboro where he received his Bachelor of Science from Joseph M. Bryan School of Business. He is either from or lived in Reidsville, NC.
McCurdy was an adjunct instructor at Tidewater Community College-Chesapeake, around 2000. He was a social studies teacher in Norfolk for 18 years. He first got into radio as president of the Education Association when he approached WPMH about getting a program on the air where he stayed for four years. Later he hosted the "Saturday Night Dance Party" on WGH. He joined WFOS in 1983, taking over as program director the same year. He was also a radio instructor for WFOS AM/Chesapeake Public Schools.
WFOS first aired in 1955 in the Oscar F. Smith High School, and covers national news via the Mutual Broadcasting System, city government, weather, and high school sports. The station stays on air 365 days a year from 6am to midnight. Notes: WPMH News is now a Christian music station (1010 AM, Portsmouth).
Scope and Content
This collection contains reel-to-reel audiotapes of interviews, speeches, and events regarding politics. Included are speeches and interviews of Henry Howell, Andrew Pickens Miller, G. Conoly Phillips, Pat Robertson, Chuck Robb, and Gerald R. Ford. Two tapes of note are a press conference of United States Senator S.I. Hayakawa from California in which he discusses the energy crisis of the late 1970s and the SALT Treaty, and a press conference of Ronald Reagan in Roanoke, Virginia during his campaign for the Presidency in 1979.
Index Terms
McCurdy, Dennis L.; United States--Politics and government--20th century; Interviews; Speeches
Contents List
- Andrew Miller (Othertype Tape 517)
- 1979 General Assembly 1979 (Othertype Tapes 529 & 532)
- 1978 Election Returns, John Dalton 1978 (Othertype Tape 533)
- Dalton Interview, 2/10/79 1979 (Othertype Tape 537)
- Nixon's Checkers Speech (Othertype Tape 546)
- Carter at JJ Dinner, 1979 1979 (Othertype Tape 555)
- Kemp at Virginia Republican Convention, Dalton, Reagan (Othertype Tape 557)
- Powell (Othertype Tape 568)
- Davis (Othertype Tape 569)
- Coleman (Othertype Tape 570)
- G. William Whitehurst, 8/27/79 1979 (Othertype 576)
- Gerald Ford, William and Mary, 10/10/79 1979 (Othertype Tape 580)
- Perspective: President Ford in Norfolk, Campaign 1978 1979 (Othertype Tape 79-9)
- S.I. Hayakawa (Othertype Tape 80-1)
- Henry Howell, Perspective 79 1979 (Othertype Tape 80-6)
- Henry Howell -- Election Night 11/8/77; June 1978 Democratic Convention (Includes Interview with Chuck Robb, and Speeches by Howell, Pat Robertson, John Warren Cooke, Conoly Phillips 1977-1978 (Othertype Tapes)